{
   "questions":[
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"1",
            "Question":"When an employee has money deducted from his paycheck to deposit into his employer’s retirement plan, the employee is contributing to his",
            "Answer":"1. 401(k) plan|2. investment portfolio|3. insurance plan|4. savings account",
            "TopicCode":"1",
            "Difficulty":"M",
            "CorrectAnswer":"1",
            "Rationale":"Rationale:  This employee is making contributions to a 401(k) retirement plan. In this type of plan, the employer may match the employee’s contributions up to a limit that is set by the employer. Employees can choose not to contribute. If they do not contribute, they lose the employer’s contribution."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"2",
            "Question":"An important consideration when deciding how to invest money being saved for emergencies is the",
            "Answer":"1. dividends being charged|2. degree of liquidity|3. limit on withdrawals|4. higher potential return",
            "TopicCode":"1",
            "Difficulty":"E",
            "CorrectAnswer":"2",
            "Rationale":"Rationale: An emergency savings account needs to be easily converted to cash (liquid). Bank savings accounts are typically very liquid and safe because they are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"3",
            "Question":"Which guideline is important to follow for successful budgeting?",
            "Answer":"1. Get a copy of the person’s three credit reports each year| 2. Know the location of the banks where accounts are held|3. Have expenses that are not greater than income|4. Earn a degree from a post-secondary education institution|",
            "TopicCode":"1",
            "Difficulty":"E",
            "CorrectAnswer":"3",
            "Rationale":"Rationale: The most important guideline to follow is to have a budget that has monthly expenses that do not exceed monthly income."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"4",
            "Question":"Which tax is the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) responsible for collecting?.",
            "Answer":"1. Sales tax|2. City tax|3. Federal income tax|4. Property tax",
            "TopicCode":"1",
            "Difficulty":"M",
            "CorrectAnswer":"3",
            "Rationale":"Rationale:  The IRS, an agency of the U.S. government, is responsible for collecting federal income taxes from people who earn income."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"5",
            "Question":"A dollar today is worth more than a dollar tomorrow best describes which economic condition?",
            "Answer":"1. Inflation|2. Deflation|3. Prosperity|4. Recession|",
            "TopicCode":"1",
            "Difficulty":"D",
            "CorrectAnswer":" 1",
            "Rationale":"Rationale: Inflation is characterized by a rise in the prices of goods and services. Therefore a dollar buys less, thus having less value. Over time, inflation occurs, making a dollar today more valuable in terms of the goods and services it can buy."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"6",
            "Question":"Jacob lost his debit card. If Jacob reports his lost or stolen debit card within two business days, he can be held responsible for",
            "Answer":"1. up to $50 unauthorized transactions|2. up to $500 unauthorized transactions|3. all unauthorized transactions without a limit|4. no purchases|",
            "TopicCode":"2",
            "Difficulty":"D",
            "CorrectAnswer":"1",
            "Rationale":"Rationale:  Under the Electronic Fund Transfer Act, if a consumer reports the theft of an EFT, ATM, or debit card to the issuing financial institution within two business days, he or she is liable for no more than $50 of unauthorized transfers."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"7",
            "Question":"When a check is made payable to cash, it",
            "Answer":"1. voids the check|2. creates a check that anyone can cash|3. does not allow the check to be deposited|4. restricts the life of the check to no more than 5 days|",
            "TopicCode":"2",
            "Difficulty":"E",
            "CorrectAnswer":"2",
            "Rationale":"Rationale: A check made payable to cash can be used by anyone in the event the check is lost or stolen. It is NOT a good idea."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"8",
            "Question":"Which of the following is a nonprofit financial institution?",
            "Answer":"1. Credit union|2. Savings and loan bank|3. Commercial bank|4. Real estate agency",
            "TopicCode":"2",
            "Difficulty":"E",
            "CorrectAnswer":"1",
            "Rationale":"Rationale: Credit unions are nonprofit financial institutions that exists to serve their members (depositors) with financial products and services.  Banks and real estate agencies are for profit business."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"9",
            "Question":"The interest rate that is paid on a bank money market account balance",
            "Answer":"1. is set at the time of the initial deposit into the money market account|2. varies depending on current interest rates|3. is determined by the date the account was opened|4. fluctuates depending on the owner’s creditworthiness",
            "TopicCode":"2",
            "Difficulty":"D",
            "CorrectAnswer":"2",
            "Rationale":"Rationale:  A bank money market account (MMA) or money market deposit account (MMDA) is a bank financial account that pays interest that varies (changes) based on current interest rates."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"10",
            "Question":"Which form of check endorsement is NOT recommended?  ",
            "Answer":"1. Blank endorsement|2. Restrictive endorsement|3. Special endorsement|4. Credit endorsement|",
            "TopicCode":"2",
            "Difficulty":"M",
            "CorrectAnswer":"1",
            "Rationale":"Rationale: A blank endorsement is a person’s signature only on the back of a check which enables anyone to cash the check.  Therefore, a blank endorsement should NOT be used unless the person is inside the financial institution when endorsing the check to deposit or cash it."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"11",
            "Question":"Which of the following information does NOT appear on a person’s credit report?",
            "Answer":"1. The outstanding balances on open accounts|2. The date and year a person opened accounts|3. The person’s current and previous addresses|4. The person’s religion and gender",
            "TopicCode":"3",
            "Difficulty":"E",
            "CorrectAnswer":"4",
            "Rationale":"Rationale: Credit reporting agencies do NOT report on religion or gender.  It is against the law for creditors to base their credit decisions on sex, age, race, color, religion, national origin, marital status, or receipt of public income or assistance."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"12",
            "Question":"When a person has to file for personal bankruptcy that allows debt to be repaid over time, she will apply to bankruptcy court for a",
            "Answer":"1. Chapter 13|2. Chapter 11|3. Chapter 10|4. Chapter 7|",
            "TopicCode":"3",
            "Difficulty":"M",
            "CorrectAnswer":"1",
            "Rationale":"Rationale:  Chapter 13, which is for personal bankruptcy, is used by people who have some equity, like a house or other property, have an income, and can meet their living expenses but not keep up with the payments on their debts. Chapter 13 allows these people to pay their debt over three to five years. Chapter 13 personal bankruptcy remains on a person’s credit report for seven years."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"13",
            "Question":"One advantage of having a home equity loan is that",
            "Answer":"1. it is interest free for the homeowner|2. it increases the value of  the person’s home|3. the interest paid on the loan is tax deductible|4. the monthly mortgage loan payments are reduced",
            "TopicCode":"3",
            "Difficulty":"D",
            "CorrectAnswer":"3",
            "Rationale":"Rationale: The interest paid on a home equity loan is tax deductible. This feature makes it attractive to people who are considering a renovation on their home or need to make costly improvements."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"14",
            "Question":"Consumer Credit Counseling Services (CCCS) offer",
            "Answer":"1. retirement plans|2. debt repayment plans|3. investment products|4. insurance policies|",
            "TopicCode":"3",
            "Difficulty":"M",
            "CorrectAnswer":"2",
            "Rationale":"Reason: Consumer Credit Counseling Services (CCCS) counsel people on how to get out of debt by developing debt repayment plans with creditors giving them part of their paycheck to pay outstanding debts. The consumer should make sure that the service is charging a reasonable fee and has a good reputation."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"15",
            "Question":"Most payday loans",
            "Answer":"1. include a fee paid to the federal government|2. are an inexpensive way to borrow|3. are extremely expensive|4. require the borrower to have a bank account",
            "TopicCode":"3",
            "Difficulty":"E",
            "CorrectAnswer":"3",
            "Rationale":"Rationale: Disadvantages of taking a payday loan are that interest rates and fees are EXTREMELY high and the borrower gets into an ongoing cycle of needing to borrow against future income. "
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"16",
            "Question":"One reason that term life insurance is usually less expensive than other types of life insurance is that this type of insurance",
            "Answer":"1. is only for a limited number of years|2. builds interest over time|3. provides coverage for a lifetime|4. is available only to consumers ages 25 to 49",
            "TopicCode":"4",
            "Difficulty":"E",
            "CorrectAnswer":"1",
            "Rationale":"Reason: Term life insurance is usually the least expensive because it only insures the individual for a limited time or “Term”. There is no cash value accumulation. The death benefit is paid only if the insured person dies during the term coverage and the limited period of time reduces the risk that the insurance company is taking."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"17",
            "Question":"A person’s new health insurance coverage will pay his claim for diabetes care, a medical condition he has had for five years. All insurance companies must allow payment of claims that are based on",
            "Answer":"1. new medical research|2. a pre-existing condition clause|3. a waiver for the premium|4. false disability|",
            "TopicCode":"4",
            "Difficulty":"M",
            "CorrectAnswer":"2",
            "Rationale":"Rationale:  Today, all health insurance policies are required to cover any pre-existing conditions."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"18",
            "Question":"An umbrella insurance policy covers",
            "Answer":"1. personal property when traveling away from home|2. flood and storm damage|3. expensive personal property such as jewelry and collections|4. major personal liability suits",
            "TopicCode":"4",
            "Difficulty":"D",
            "CorrectAnswer":"4",
            "Rationale":"Rationale: An umbrella policy provides a great deal of additional coverage to protect against a lawsuit that could be brought over injuries andor property damage that the policyholder caused that exceeds the liability limits on his car insurance, home insurance, boat insurance, etc."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"19",
            "Question":"Which of the following insurance policies generally covers the cost of a stolen car for the policyholder?",
            "Answer":"1. Mortgage|2. Homeowners|3. Automobile|4. Life|",
            "TopicCode":"4",
            "Difficulty":"E",
            "CorrectAnswer":"3",
            "Rationale":"Rationale: Automobile comprehensive insurance covers the theft of motor vehicles, injuries to the driver and passengers, and possible damage to the other car and its occupants in an accident. However, not all auto policies cover theft."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"20",
            "Question":"How does the degree of risk, that the insurance company has to take, influence the cost of the insurance policy?",
            "Answer":"1. The lower the risk, the higher the cost of the insurance premium|2. The higher the risk, the higher the cost of the insurance premium|3. The higher the risk, the lower the cost of the insurance premium|4. There is no relationship between the risk and the cost of the insurance premium",
            "TopicCode":"4",
            "Difficulty":"M",
            "CorrectAnswer":"2",
            "Rationale":"Rationale:  The higher the risk for the insurance company, the higher the cost of the premium for the insurance policy."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"21",
            "Question":"A person sold her stock in ABC Company for a higher price per share than she bought it for. Therefore, she had a capital",
            "Answer":"1. gain|2. loss|3. surplus|4. dividend|",
            "TopicCode":"5",
            "Difficulty":"E",
            "CorrectAnswer":"1",
            "Rationale":"Rationale: If a person sells stock for a higher price per share than she bought it for, she has made a profit which is called a capital gain. If the person sells it for less than she bought it for, she has a capital loss. Sale price – purchase price = capital gain or loss."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"22",
            "Question":"A woman wants to buy an investment that will pay a fixed dividend, providing a source of steady retirement income. Which investment product best meets her needs?",
            "Answer":"1. Preferred stock|2. Speculative stock|3. Common stock|4. Capital growth stock|",
            "TopicCode":"5",
            "Difficulty":"D",
            "CorrectAnswer":"1",
            "Rationale":"Rationale: Preferred stock is issued with a fixed dividend per share. The regular dividend payments appeal to retired investors and others who desire a reliable stream of income."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"23",
            "Question":"The advantage of mutual funds is that they are",
            "Answer":"1. an investment portfolio managed by the investor|2. an investment that holds a wide range of different investments instruments, providing diversification|3. usually less risky than investing in a savings account|4. guaranteed to increase in value",
            "TopicCode":"5",
            "Difficulty":"E",
            "CorrectAnswer":"2",
            "Rationale":"Rationale:  A mutual fund’s investment portfolio typically holds between 100 and 200 different types of investment instruments, including, for example, stocks, bonds, and money market securities. This diversification minimizes the investor’s risk. A mutual fund’s portfolio is managed by a professional fund manager which may be advantageous to an inexperienced investor. They are not guaranteed to increase in value."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"24",
            "Question":"If a business corporation wants to raise capital but NOT create debt, it can",
            "Answer":"1. issue a bond|2. issue common stock|3. borrow money from a commercial bank|4. borrow money from the government",
            "TopicCode":"5",
            "Difficulty":"M",
            "CorrectAnswer":"2",
            "Rationale":"Rationale:  A corporation raises capital (money) when it issues stock, a share in the ownership of the company. Issuing stock does not create a debt. Issuing bonds or borrowing money from a financial institution or the government does create debt for the company."
         }
      },
      {
         "Question":{
            "QuestionID":"25",
            "Question":"An individual does NOT want to pay federal income tax on investment earnings. Therefore it is advisable for this person to buy",
            "Answer":"1. corporate bonds|2. growth stocks|3. stock mutual funds|4. municipal bonds",
            "TopicCode":"5",
            "Difficulty":"D",
            "CorrectAnswer":"4",
            "Rationale":"Rationale: The interest earned on municipal bonds is tax-free (although a person may have some taxes, depending on the type of municipal bond).The income received from dividends on stocks and mutual funds is taxable income. The interest earned on savings accounts is taxable income."
         }
      }
   ]
}